Guide to the Cornell University Department of Entomology records, 1927-2014.
Department of Entomology records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Department of Entomology records, 1927-2014.
21-23-2133
New York State College of Agriculture. Dept. of Entomology.
27.4 cubic ft.
Computer Media, Manuscripts, Printed Materials, Publications, Research Materials, Photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the Cornell University Department of Entomology in Ithaca and at the NYS Agricultural Experiment Station.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of the Cornell University Department of Entomology in Ithaca and at the NYS Agricultural Experiment Station, including department reviews and correspondence of Charles Palm when he was the Director.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture.; Palm, Charles Edmund, 1911-
Subjects:
Entomology.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
See also the collection of glass slides pertaining to the Department of Entomology insect collections, located in the mezzanine. Index of slides stored with slide cabinets.
RELATED MATERIALS
See also Cornell University Department of Entomology and Limnology records, #21-23-1461, and the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station records, #22-1-44 http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RMA01461.
CONTAINER LIST
- Charles C. Palm Records
  - Correspondence
  - A-R, 1938-1939 (Box 1)
  - R-Z, 1938-1939 (Box 2)
  - A-L, 1939-1940 (Box 2)
  - L-Z, 1939-1940 (Box 3)
  - A-D, 1940-1941 (Box 3)
  - D-Z, 1940-1941 (Box 4)
  - A-N, 1941-1942 (Box 5)
  - N-Z, 1941-1942 (Box 6)
  - A-L, 1942-1943 (Box 6)
  - A-L, 1942-1943 (Box 7)
  - M-Z, 1943-1944 (Box 8)
  - A-O, 1944-1945 (Box 9)
  - O-Z, 1944-1945 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1946-1947 (Box 10)
  - Department File, Prior to 1938 (Box 11)
  - Department File, Prior to 1938 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 13)
  - R-Z, 1945-1946 (Box 14)
  - A-Z, 1946-1947 (Box 15)
  - D-G, 1946-1948 (Box 16)
  - G-Z, 1947-1948 (Box 17)
  - A-Z, 1947-1948 (Box 18)
  - A-G, 1947-1948 (Box 19)
  - G-Z, 1948-1949 (Box 20)
  - Department of Entomology Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 20)
  - Department of Entomology Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence and Schwartz Reprints, 1953-1954 (Box 24)
  - United Fruit Company Correspondence, 1950-1959 (Box 28)
  - Letter from Carl Robert Osten Sachen, a Russian Diplomat and Entomologist, 1903 (Box 29)
  - Other Subject Files
  - Graduate Students, 1950 (Box 25)
  - Charles C. Palm Letters, 1949-1955 (Box 25)
  - Visiting Lectures, 1950 (Box 25)
  - Charles C. Palm Personal File (Box 26)
  - Charles C. Palm Personal File (Box 27)
  - Comstock Library of Entomology - Periodical Titles, 1970 (Box 28)
  - Vegetable and Potato Insect Control Recommendations - Ray Kriner, 1956 (Box 29)
  - Department Review Reports, Ithaca and Geneva, 1973; 1984; 2006 (Box 29)
  - Programs from Events for the Centennial of Entomology at Cornell, 1974 (Box 29)
  - Program from "Insectapalooza Celebrates the Sesquicentennial - 150 Years 150 Bugs", 2014 (Box 29)
  - Photographs
  - Department of Entomology - Group Photos and Various Other Photos, 1920s-1950s (Box 29)
  - James George Needham Photos, no dates (Box 29)